Charles Coleman Sellers Collection ca.1940-1978 Mss.Ms.Coll.3
American Philosophical Society
- Series V. Paintings by the Peales (Box 24-31)
  - Renault. Washington at Yorktown
  - Ridgely, David. Minature. Rembrandt?
  - Rodney, Mrs. Caesar, and daughter. Not by C. W. Peale.
  - St.-Memin CWPeale
  - Sanders,??
  - Sanders, John
  - Sellers, Anna
  - Sellers, Coleman, and wife, Mrs. Sophonisba Anguiscola Peale
  - Sellers, George Escol
  - Sellers, George Escol. Washington on the Raritan
  - Sellers, Nathan, at "Milbank"
  - Sellers, Mrs. Sophonisba Anguiscola Peale
  - Shell, Henry?
  - Simmons, William
  - Steele, Byron
  - Stevens, John, and Rachel Cox Peale???
  - Stuart, Gilbert Rembrandt?
  - Taylor, Robert, or Alexander. Rembrandt?
  - Thompson, Robert "Blue" Rembrandt?
  - Tingley, Samuel, 1740-1800
  - "Vestier painting his wife."
  - Wall, James, by Cosmo Alexander
  - Washington minature??
  - Weiser
  - Whelan, Thomas A Rembrandt? Sarah??
  - Unattributed
    - Architect
    - Artist, c.1770
    - Boy. Minature. B.West?
    - "Caritas" Peale?
    - Girl
    - Lady Ganci
    - Lady (Mourot)
    - Lady 1800 CWPeale?
    - Lady Ayotte?
    - Lady CWPeale? Kindig
    - Man and woman
    - Man Brandeis
    - Man Zoffany?
    - Mother and child. not CWPeale
    - Navigation instrument maker, c.1730-40
    - Pennsylvania Dutch couple. CWPeale??
    - Three boys
  - West, Benjamin. "Coriolanus." "Agrippina in the Roman Corps."
  - Wyeth
- Series VI. Artists' File (Box 32-33)
  - Abbey, Edwin Austin
  - Allston, Washington
  - Alexander, John White
  - Bellows, George
  - Benbridge, Henry
  - Boughton
  - Bingham, George Caleb
  - Brown, Mather
  - Ceracchi, Giuseppe
  - Claypoole, James
  - Cole, Thomas
  - Conarroe, George Washington
  - Copley, John Singleton
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr
  - Debufé, Edouard
  - Delaplaine, Joseph
  - Dielman, Frederick
  - du Maurier, George
  - Dunlap, William
  - Durand, Ashur B
  - Eakins, Thomas
  - Earl [Earle], Ralph
  - Eichholtz, Jacob
  - Feke, Robert
  - Field, Erastus Salisbury
  - Field, Robert
  - Frymire, Jacob
  - Fuller, George
  - Gilbert, Michel G
  - Greenough, Horatio
  - Guy, Francis
  - Haidt, John Valentine
  - Harding, Chester
  - Harrison, Birge
  - Healy, George Peter Alexander
  - Hesselius, John
  - Homer, Winslow
  - Hovenden, Thomas
  - Hunt, William Morris
  - Inman,Henry
  - Inness, George
  - Johnston, Joshua
  - Krimmel, J L
  - Lafarge, John
  - Landseer, Sir Edwin
  - Leslie, Charles Robert
  - Leutze, Emanuel
  - Martin, John
  - Millet, Jean François
  - Leigh, William Robinson
  - Leslie, Charles R
  - McMurtrie, James
  - Morse, Samuel Finley Breeze
  - Munkacsy, Michael de
  - Neagle, John
  - Officer, Thomas S
  - Parrish, Maxfield
  - Peale, Patrick
  - Pine, Robert Edge
  - Powers, Hiram
  - Pyle, Howard
  - Rembrandt Artist drawing from a model.
  - Remington, Frederick
  - Roesen, Severin
  - Rudy, Charles
  - Rush, William
  - Ryder, Albert P
  - Sartain, John
  - Schussele, C
  - Seymour
  - Smibert, John
  - Smith, Thomas
  - Steward, Joseph
  - Stuart, Gilbert
  - Sully, Thomas
  - Sully (perhaps one of his masters in England)
  - Thackara, William, Jr.
  - Trenchard, James
  - Trumbull, John
  - Vanderlyn, John
  - Vedder, Elihu
  - West, Benjamin
    - Christ rejected
    - Pale horse
    - Penn's treaty
    - Pennsylvania Hospital
  - Whistler, James Abbott McNeill
  - Wollaston, John
- Series VII. Correspondence (Box 34-35)
  The correspondence pertaining to artistic subjects has been kept as arranged by Charles Coleman Sellers. Larger blocks of correspondence pertaining to a single subject have been listed separately.
  - American Philosophical Society
  - Amherst College
  - Art, etc.
  - B
  - Barroll, Louis Keene
  - Bevan, Mrs. Edith R
  - C
  - Carnegie Institute
  - D
  - De Puy, Herbert
  - Detroit Institute of Art
  - E
  - F
  - Frick Art Reference Library
  - H
  - Hergesheimer, E H
  - J
  - K
  - L
  - Leary, Lewis
  - M
  - McCandless, Byron H
  - Marceau, Henri
  - Meade, Edward K
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art
  - N
  - National Gallery
  - Newark Museum
  - O
  - P
  - Parke, Lila G
  - in re Peale, C. W.
  - Peale descendants
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts
  - Pleasants, J Hall
  - Princeton University
  - Purcell, T Noel de'L
  - R
  - S
  - Stringham, Emerson
  - T
  - Tilghman, Benjamin Chew
  - U
  - V
  - Virginia Historical Society
  - W
  - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art
  - Worcester Museum
  - Young, Henry S
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous materials
  - 1 Charles Willson Peale autobiography
  - 2 Charles Willson Peale autobiography (index)
  - 3 Charles Willson Peale chronology, 2 vols.
  - 4 Charles Willson Peale diaries (partial typescript)
  - 5 Charles Willson Peale genealogy and descendants
  - 6 Charles Willson Peale letterbooks (index)
  - 7 Charles Willson Peale calendar
  - 8 Charles Willson Peale portraits of George Washington, 2 vols.
  - 9 James Peale
  - 10 Rembrandt Peale, 2 vols.
  - 11 Peale's Museum chronology, by H. W. Sellers
  - 12 Peale's Museum materials
  - 13 Peale Family Genealogy (index)
  - 14 Physiognotrace
  - 15 Peale's Museum
  - 16 George Escol Sellers. Autobiography (with index), 2 vols.
  - 17 Peale family recipe book
  - 18 Notes for Patron and Populace. Card file
  - 19 1776 Washington (not Peale and unidentified). Card file